<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Learner" icon="doseresponseIcon.png">
    <name>Dose Response (R)</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Calculates and visualizes dose response curves
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>Calculates and visualizes dose response curves. This is achieved by fitting several non-linear regression
                models to your data. 
                <br/>
                Measurements are grouped per <i>Compound</i> and <i>Concentration</i> (see Options).<br/>
                Measurements from a zero concentration are used to calculate the fit but are not displayed in the plot
                because of its logarithmic scale.
                <br/>
                For a conceptual and technical overview have a look at "Bioassay Analysis using R", Ritz and Streibig,
                2005, 5:12, Journal of Statistical Software.
            </p>
            <p>
                <u>IMPORTANT:</u>
                <br/>
                This node is using R as back end, make sure that Rserve is running somewhere, and KNIME is accordingly
                configured (KNIME->Preferences).
                <a href="https://github.com/knime-mpicbg/knime-scripting/wiki/R-server-for-knime">HCS-Tools Wiki</a>
            </p>
        </intro>
        
        <tab name = "Script Editor">

	        <option name="Parameters of interest">The assay parameters for which a dose response analysis should be carried
	            out.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Compound">The column containing the compound information (group1)
	        </option>
	        <option name="Concentration">The column containing the concentrations (group2)
	        </option>
	        <option name="Plot title">Adds a custom main title to the plot
	        </option>
	
	        <option name="Regression Model">The following models (referred to their abbreviation in the configuration
	            dialog) are supported:
	            <ol>
	                <li>LL.3 : Three-parameter logistic</li>
	                <li>LL.4 : Four-parameter logistic (default)</li>
	                <li>LL.5 : Five-parameter logistic</li>
	                <li>W1.2 : Two-parameter Weibull</li>
	                <li>W1.3 : Three-parameter Weibull</li>
	                <li>W1.4 : Four-parameter Weibull</li>
	            </ol>
	            For a mathematical model definition see <a href="https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/drc/drc.pdf">Package 'drc'</a>
	        </option>
	        <option name="Plotting Options"> Several plot options additional to the dose response curve are available:
	        	<ol>
	        		<li>Data points - single measurements</li>
	        		<li>SEM - standard error of the mean (default)</li>
	        		<li>SD - standard deviation</li>
	        	</ol>
	        </option>
	
	        <option name="Parameter constraints">Allows to set constraints for some or all parameters of the model. This
	            requires
	            knowledge about the model structure, which can be obtained easily using R (e.g. just type ?LL.4 for the
	            configuration of the 4-parametric logistic model. Use NA for no constraint.
	            <br/>
	            Example for LL.4 which imposes a upper limit at 3: NA, NA, 3, NA
	        </option>
        
        </tab>
        <tab name = "Chunk Settings">
        	<option name="Several settings">
        	Settings to transfer the data between KNIME and R in chunks (only necessary for very big tables)
        	For documentation please check out the node description of the <i>RSnippet</i> node.
        	</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name = "Output Options">
        	<option name="Several settings">
        	Settings to control plot size and whether it should be exported as file.
        	For documentation please check out the node description of the <i>RPlot</i> node.
        	</option>
        </tab>

    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="dose response data">A table with dose response data
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="parameter table">A table which contains ic50s, model parameters, and error estimates
        </outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="dose response plot">The generated dose response curve plotted as PNG-image 
        </outPort>
        <outPort index="2" name="model">An R list with all dose response models for further analysis
        </outPort>

    </ports>

    <views>
        <view index="0" name="R-Plot">R-Plot with dose response curve
        </view>
    </views>

</knimeNode>
