<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">

<knimeNode icon="./excelicon.png" type="Source">

    <name>MotionTracking Reader</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Reads a list of MotionTracking Reader '.csv'-export-files into Knime.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>

        <intro>Reads a list of MotionTracking '.csv'-export-files into Knime. This is done by searching for csv-files
            recursively within the specified directory or by selecting a list of files directly.
        </intro>

        <option name="Input Files">
            <p>There are two modes of operation. Either you can choose a single directory in which
                the nodes will search for MotionTracking files. The search is applied not only to the direct directory
                contents but also to also its subfolders.
                <br/>
                The second mode is to select a set of files (by keeping the apple/windows-key pressed while selecting
                files).
                <br/>
                In the advanced tab of the configuration dialog one can define the pattern and associate the keywords to
                interpret the information of the file Paths contained in the first column. The default pattern is:
                <br/>
                <b>
                    <![CDATA[
                (?<barcode>.*)__(?<row>[0-9]{3})(?<column>[0-9]{3})[0-9]{3}_(?<timpoint>[0-9]{1})(?<wellfield>[0-9]{3})[.]mtf
                ]]> </b>
                <br/>

                This pattern matches file paths from images acquired with the Opera (Perkin Elmer) and that are
                converted
                with motion tracking into mtf-files. Anything that is contained within () -> token, will be associated
                with
                the variable that is contained within. The rest of the syntax is normal regular expressions (see
                java-doc).
            </p>

            <p>
                The mandatory variables are
                <br/>
                <i>barcode</i>
                <br/>
                <i>row</i>
                <br/>
                <i>column</i>
                <br/>
            </p>

            <p>The optional variables are:
                <br/>
                <i>timepoint</i>: time point between scans
                <br/>
                <i>wellfield</i>: field of view within one well
                <br/>
                <i>frame</i>: can be a time-frame of a movie or a z-slice of a z-stack (usually not used in HCS).
            </p>
            Thus another example for the same type of paths:
            <br/>
            <b>
                <![CDATA[
            (?<barcode>.*)__(?<row>[0-9]{3})(?<column>[0-9]{3})(?<frame>[0-9]{3})_(?<timpoint>[0-9]{1})(?<wellfield>[0-9]{3})[.]mtf
            ]]>
            </b>
        </option>

    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="data-table">The imported MotionTracking-data</outPort>
    </ports>

</knimeNode>
