<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">

<knimeNode icon="./excelicon.png" type="Source">

    <name>Combine Columns by Header</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Combines the content of a set of columns.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>

        <intro>
            <p>
                IMPORTANT: This node will ignore the user-defined new column name and will use an auto-generated one.
                Combines the content of a set of columns and appends the concatenated string as separate column to the
                input table. The user needs to specify in the dialog the columns of interest and some other properties,
                such as delimiter to separate the different cell contents and quoting options. This node works well
                together with the “Combine Columns by Header” node.
            </p>

            <p>
                Example:
                <br/>

                Plate Row Column
                <br/>

                Plate01 A 1
                <br/>

                Plate02 A 2
                <br/>

                Combined by “::”
                <br/>

                Plate::Row::Column
                <br/>

                Plate01::A::1
                <br/>

                Plate02::A::2
                <br/>
            </p>

            This Combine node automatically gives new column names (“Name of appended column” field will be ignored)
        </intro>

        <option name="Delimiter">
            Enter a delimiter string here. This string is used to separate the different cell contents in the new,
            appended column.
        </option>
        <option name="Quote Character">The character entered here will be used to quote the cell content in case that it
            contains the delimiter string (for instance if the cell content is some;value, the delimiter string is ';'
            (a single semicolon), and the quote character is '"' (single quote char) the quoted string will be
            "some;value" (including quotes)). You can force quotation by checking "Quote Always". Alternatively, the
            user can also replace the delimiter string in the cell content string (see below).
        </option>
        <option name="Replace Delimiter by">If the string representation of the cell content contains the delimiter
            string, it will be replaced by the string entered here (if you entered '-' here, the output of the above
            example would be some-value).
        </option>
        <option name="Name of appended column">Auto-generated new column name (editing this field will be ignored).
        </option>
        <option name="Column Selection">Move the columns of interest into the "Include" list.</option>

    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="input">Arbitrary input data.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="output">Input data + additional column containing string combination</outPort>
    </ports>

</knimeNode>
