<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./SSMD.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>SSMD (PC x NC)</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Calculates SSMDs (strictly standardized mean difference) for all combinations of a selection of negative and a
        selection of positive
        controls.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
                The SSMD (strictly standardized mean difference) is a statistical parameter that describes the quality
                of an assay or a screening plate.
                It takes into account the separation and the variabilities of two controls (e.g. positive and negative
                control wells) and ranges from plus to minus infinity.
                The SSMD as an alternative to the Z-Prime factor is a bit easier to interpret because it behaves similar
                as the Z score.
            </p>
            <p>
                For groups of data (e.g. wells of plates) SSMDs are calculated for two selected subsets (e.g. positive
                and negative control wells of a plate).
                Multiple positive and negative controls can be selected as subsets and the SSMDs will be calculated for
                all combinations of these.
                For each group mean and standard deviation (or median and mad) are calculated for the selected subsets.
            </p>
            <p>
                SSMD = (mean(x[subset{positive}]) - mean(x[subset{negative}])) / sqrt(sd(x[subset{positive}])² +
                sd(x[subset{negative}])²)
                <br/>
                or
                <br/>
                SSMD = (median(x[subset{positive}]) - median(x[subset{negative}])) / sqrt(mad(x[subset{positive}])² +
                mad(x[subset{negative}])²)
            </p>
            <p>
                Literature: Zhang, X., Genomics 89 (2007) 552–561
                <br/>
                <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SSMD">Wikipedia: SSMD</a>
            </p>
        </intro>

        <option name="Group wells by">Select the column to define the groups (e.g. "barcode" for plate-wise SSMDs).
        </option>
        <option name="Subset column / well annotation column">Column with well annotations (e.g. treatment)
        </option>
        <option name="Subset / Positive Control">Select subsets as positive controls for which means and sd (medians and
            mads) are calculated for each group.
        </option>
        <option name="Subset / Negative Control">Select subsets as negative controls for which means and sd (medians and
            mads) are calculated for each group.
        </option>
        <option name="Use robust statistics">Median and mad will be calculated instead of mean and sd.
        </option>
        <option name="Include">Select the columns for which SSDMs will be calculated.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <!-- input -->
        <inPort index="0" name="In-Port name">Input table</inPort>
        <!-- output -->
        <outPort index="0" name="Out-Port name">Table with SSMDs</outPort>
    </ports>

</knimeNode>