<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./bargraph.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>BinningAnalysis</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Object based data is binned based on the density distribution of a reference population. For each bin a z-score
        is returned.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            For each chosen column (parameter) a reference population is used to estimate n different bins. The bins are
            based on the quantiles of the data.
            Then all data is grouped by the aggregation label (e.g. well) and the data of each group is applied to the
            bins.
            The percentage of data falling into a certain bin is calculated and used to estimate a z-score.
            The result contains a z-score, a percentage and an absolute count for each bin of each aggregation group and
            each parameter.
            It should help to detect minor distribution changes which would not be caught with a mean or median per
            aggregation group of the object data.
        </intro>

        <option name="Aggregate object data by">object data of each subgroup will be applied to the bins (e.g. well)
        </option>
        <option name="Column selection">the data of the selected columns will be used for the binning analysis (e.g.
            different parameters)
        </option>
        <option name="Number of bins">the reference population is divided into the given number of bins</option>
        <option name="Column with reference label">the chosen column contains the label to describe the reference
            population.
            If all data should be used as reference population, the option can be set to "None"
        </option>
        <option name="Subset by">if a reference population should be used, the chosen label defines this subpopulation
        </option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="object data">Table containing object based data</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="binned data">Result of the binning analysis</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
