<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Source">
    <name>Correlation</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Calculates the correlation coefficients between corresponding groups from different subsets.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>The output will be a new table that contains the as many rows as possible permutations between the
            subsets
            times the number of groups. The selector to define variables can also exclude all columns.
            <br/>
            Note that you should use the nominal filter to make a selection of the subsets and groups. Otherwise the
            correlation
            table will become huge and the calculation will last a long, long time.
        </intro>
        <option name="Correlation Method">For measuring correlation there are the Pearson-Correlation-Coefficient and
            the
            Spearman-Correlation-Coefficient available.
        </option>
        <option name="Subsets">Select the columns by which the measurements should be grouped (example: plates,
            batches, runs...)
        </option>
        <option name="Column Filter function">where it says "Use the following colum-filter for:", one can choose
            between
            the "batch-processing" modus, that calculates correlation between the subsets that have in all selected
            columns
            the same values. The "measurement-association" mode allows to associate measurement between subsets.
        </option>
        <option name="Constraints">(First column filter) select one or more column to define the groups within the
            subsets.
            A particular group has the same value for all the selected columns.
        </option>
        <option name="Readout Selection">Select the parameter to be correlated. If multiple parameter are calculated,
            The correlation value represents the average fingerprint correlation of a particular group.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="screen">input screen to be QC'ed</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="correlation">A table containg a row for each subset and group and the corresponding
            correlation values.
        </outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>

    <!--<views>-->
    <!--<view index="0" name="ScreenExplorer">A heatmap visualization tool</view>-->
    <!--view index="1" name="name of second view">Description of second view...</view-->
    <!--</views>-->

</knimeNode>
