<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Source">
    <name>Multivariate Z-Primes</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Calculates the multivariate z-prime coefficients for all combinations of a selection of negative and a selection
        of positive
        controls over a gives set of groups.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>The output will be a new table that contains the as many rows as groups and as many columns sets as
            possible permutations between positive and negative controls times the number of groups.
            <br/>
            The output is the multivariate Z' factor and the classification error, an additional measure of how good the
            positive
            and negative control measurments seperate. Additionally for each control there is the
            number of samples and the status. The computation of the covariance matrix requires as many observations as
            parameter (rows as columns). So if this criteria is not met, the algorithm tries to bootstrap the matrix.
            If there are less than 3 observations, no Zprime is calculated (untrustworthy).
            <br/>
            The multivariate Z' factors are implemented acoording to the Paper from Anne Kümmel:
            "Integration of Multiple Readouts into the Z' Factor for Assay Quality Assessment"
            (http://jbx.sagepub.com/content/15/1/95)
            <br/>
            Note that the nature of the distributions from positive and negative control should be similar. The best
            results
            are obtained if the distributions are multivariate normal.
        </intro>
        <option name="Group by">Select the columns by which the measurements should be grouped (example: plates,
            batches, runs...)
        </option>
        <option name="Treatment attribute">The treatement attribute defines the column of the table where to find the
            positive
            and negative controls.
        </option>
        <option name="Positive Controls">Here the positive controls are selected on which to compute the multivariate
            Z' factors against the Negative controls.
        </option>
        <option name="Negative Controls">Here the negative controls are selected.
        </option>
        <option name="Readout Selection">Allows to select the readouts that will be used to compute the multivariate
            z-primes
            will be calcuated
        </option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="screen">input screen to be QC'ed</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="z-primes">A table containg a row for each plate with all z-primes as attributes.
        </outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>

    <!--<views>-->
    <!--<view index="0" name="ScreenExplorer">A heatmap visualization tool</view>-->
    <!--view index="1" name="name of second view">Description of second view...</view-->
    <!--</views>-->

</knimeNode>
