<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Z-Primes (PC x NC)</name>

    <shortDescription>
        The node calculates Z-Prime factors (Z') for all combinations of selected positive and negative controls.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
                The Z-Prime factor is a commonly used statistical parameter that describes the quality of an assay or a
                screening plate.
                It takes into account the separation and the variabilities of two controls (e.g. positive and negative
                control wells) and ranges from minus infinity to 1.
            </p>
            <p>
                For groups of data (e.g. wells of plates) Z-Prime factors are calculated for two selected subsets (e.g.
                positive and negative control wells of a plate).
                Multiple positive and negative controls can be selected as subsets and the Z-Prime factors will be
                calculated for all combinations of these.
                For each group mean and standard deviation (or median and mad) are calculated for the selected subsets.
            </p>
            <p>
                Z' = 1 - 3 * (sd(x[subset{positive}]) + sd(x[subset{negative}])) / |mean(x[subset{positive}]) -
                mean(x[subset{negative}])|
                <br/>
                or
                <br/>
                Z' = 1 - 3 * (mad(x[subset{positive}]) + mad(x[subset{negative}])) / |median(x[subset{positive}]) -
                median(x[subset{negative}])|
            </p>
            <p>
                Literature: Zhang, J. et al., J Biomol Screen 1999; 4; 67
                <br/>
                <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Z-factor">Wikipedia: Z-factor</a>
            </p>
        </intro>

        <option name="Group wells by">Select the column to define the groups (e.g. "barcode" for plate-wise Z-Prime
            factor).
        </option>
        <option name="Subset column / well annotation column">Column with well annotations (e.g. treatment)
        </option>
        <option name="Subset / Positive Control">Select subsets as positive controls for which means and sd (medians and
            mads) are calculated for each group.
        </option>
        <option name="Subset / Negative Control">Select subsets as negative controls for which means and sd (medians and
            mads) are calculated for each group.
        </option>
        <option name="Use robust statistics">Median and mad will be calculated instead of mean and sd.
        </option>
        <option name="Include">Select the columns for which Z-Prime factors will be calculated.
        </option>

    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <!-- input -->
        <inPort index="0" name="In-Port name">Input table</inPort>
        <!-- output -->
        <outPort index="0" name="Out-Port name">Table with Z-Prime factors</outPort>
    </ports>

</knimeNode>
