<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./heatmap-viewer.png" type="Visualizer">

    <name>Plate Heatmap Viewer</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Creates trellis of plate heatmaps to explore a set of microtiter plates (High Content Screen Data).
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Creates trellis of heatMaps to explore your screen.
            By default nodes expects three columns to be present in order to reorder wells back into plates:<br/>
            - barcode<br/>
            - plateRow<br/>
            - plateColumn<br/>
            <br/>
            Mouse behaviour:<br/>
            The heatmap trellis and the individual plate view support single selection and drag-selection.<br/>
            Right click on a plate of the trellis opens an individual plate view. A right click on a well of the plate
            view opens an a well detail view.<br/>
            <br/>
            Supported <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microtiter_plate">microtiter plate</a> formats:<br/>
            6, 12, 24, 96, 384 and 1536. The viewer will try to make a guess about the proper plate dimension if not
            all wells are present in the table (e.g. because outer rows are not used).<br/>
            <br/>
            Image data:<br/>
            Tables containing images allow visualization of the well images in the well detail view. Any cell of an image
            data column will be visualized. So far the KNIME native PNG images are recognised, as well as the formats
            provided by the <a href="http://tech.knime.org/community/image-processing">Image Processing</a> plugin.
            Careful! the processing might take time and disk space. The best performance is achieved with the "Image
            Reference" produced by the "Image File Linker" node of the image processing plugin.
        </intro>
        <option name="Readouts">
            A selection of readouts which should be displayed by the viewer. Especially for
            high-content screens with many readouts (100+), you may want to include just a subset them. This will help
            to prevent memory problems.
        </option>
        <option name="Factors">
            Annotation column that further characterize the wells.
        </option>
        <option name="Barcode">
            Select column to assign barcode (string or integer).
        </option>
        <option name="Row">
            Select column to assign row value (integer, 1 to 16 refers to A to P).
        </option>
        <option name="Column">
            Select column to assign column value (integer, 1 to 24).
        </option>
        <option name="Plate Label">
            Column that is used to extract the plate label, which should allow easy identification of the plate.
        </option>
        <option name="Controls">
            The <b>subset column</b> allows to choose a nominal attribute, which allows to identify control populations.<br/>
            Select one ore several <b>reference groups</b>. These can be used to define custom color maps
            (gray out or mark the populations range with a special color).
        </option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Screen Data Table">
            A table containing High Content Screening data.
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="The same screen without any changes">
            Same as input table.
        </outPort>
    </ports>

    <views>
        <view index="0" name="Plate Heatmap Trellis">
            Trellis containing all heatmaps representing the plates of the screen.
        </view>
    </views>

</knimeNode>
