<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./BinningApplyNode.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Binning Apply</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
    	This node applies a binning model.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	<p>
        	The incoming data is grouped based on the node settings for grouping. 
        	Within each group and for each column of the incoming binning model, data points are counted for each bin. 
        	Further, data points with values below the lowest bin get counted as well as data points with values above the
        	highest bin. Missing values will no be counted.<br/>
        	The first output table contains these counts and the corresponding percentage within the group.
        	The counts of the lowest interval will include (!) the counts below; and the counts of the highest interval
        	will include the counts above. So the sum reflects the number of data points of the group and percentages
        	sum up to 100%.<br/>
        	The second output table only contains counts of data points with values below the lowest or above the highest interval.
        	The percentage is based on the data point count.
        	
			</p>
        </intro>
        
        <tab name="General settings">
        <option name="Group columns">
       		Included columns will be used to group the data.
        </option>
        <option name="Exclude incomplete binning models">
        <p>
        	Models with less than n bins will be excluded. Number of expected bins is part of the binning model.<br/>
        	default: checked
        </p>
        </option>
        <option name="Ignore missing columns">
        <p>
        	If checked only a warning will be shown if incoming data table does miss columns which are contained in the binning model.
        	If unchecked, the node will not be executable if any column is missing.<br/>
        	default: checked
        	</p>
        </option>
        <option name="Input is already sorted by group column(s)">
        	<p>
        	If checked, the data will not be sorted during execution (faster). The node will fail if the pre-sorting is not correct.<br/>
        	default: unchecked
        	</p>
        </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Sampling options">
        <option name="Enable sampling">
       		<p>
       		If checked, each group will be reduced (randomly) to a fixed number of rows, which can be set.
       		If the group does contain less rows, all will be used.<br/>
       		default: 100
       		</p>
        </option>
        <option name="Use random seed">
       		<p>
       		If checked, the random selection of rows for the sampling will be based on a fixed seed to make it reproducible.
       		</p>
        </option>
        </tab>

    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input Data">Data to apply the binning model to</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Binning Model">Binning model</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Counts">
        	Row counts per group, parameter and interval <br/>(including outlier count within the lowest/highest interval)
        </outPort>  
        <outPort index="1" name="Outlier counts">Row counts per group, parameter and interval of datapoints below lowest or above highest interval</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>